

# **David Thonnard**

Neuroscientist Data-analyst

P July 26, 1985 (36)

🔽 Leuven, Belgium

+32 498 07 56 51

@ thonnard.david@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/Thonnard

github.com/Thonnard/

## About Me —

I am a neuroscientist and data scientist with a biomedical and psychological background. For the past 8 years, I have been conducting preclinical work studying cognitive flexibility. During this period, I have also developped a wide array of statistical and data-related skills. More recently. I have been combining academia with industry.

# Languages -

Dutch **English** French Spanish German

# Hard Skills -

▲ Laboratory Skills

Neurosurgical lesions

Neurosurgical implantations

IHC/nissl stainings

Brain perfusion/extraction

✓ Injections (IP/SC/IM)

Optogenetics

Flowcytometry

## **Work Experience**

currently **Research Scientist** UCB

In-vivo pharmacology - neurodegeneration - gene therapy

2020-2021 **QA Analyst/Consultant** 

Quality Assuruance in the European Distribrution Center (EDC) for Medical Devices (Johnson & Johnson) as consultant for Altran -

Capgemini.

2013-2020 Neuroscientist KU Leuven - Brain and Cognition

Preclinical brain research. Main topic: cognitive flexibility. Lab of

Prof. Dr. Rudi D'Hooge.

2008 Lab technician University Ghent - Dep. of Virology

> Quantification of cellular immunological memory after measles vaccination through intracellular cytokine detection using flowcytometry.

Lab of Prof. Dr. Geert Leroux-Roels.

#### Education

currently **Advanced Master in Artificial Intelligence** KU Leuven

**Engineering and Computer Science** 

2014-2020 **PhD Neuroscience** KU Leuven

Thesis: Pharmacological mechanisms and telencephalic interactions

involved in neurocognitive flexibility

2008-2013 Master of Science in Theoretical and Experimental Ghent University

**Psychology** 

Thesis: Jouw pijn is mijn pijn, maar... "Does it matter if you're black

or white?".

2005-2008 **Bachelor in Biomedic Laboratory** University College - Ghent

Technology, Pharmaceutical and Biological

**Techniques** 

Thesis: Quantification of cellular immunological memory after

measles vaccination through intracellular cytokine detection.

#### Grants

2014 Doctoraatsbeurs Strategisch Basisonderzoek IWT/FWO

### Conferences & Presentations

08/2017 **European Behavioural Pharmacology Society** Heraklion - Greece

Perseverative behaviour in low-dose MK801-treated mice

07/2017 **RIKEN Brain Science Institute** Tokyo - Japan

Impaired reversal learning after NMDA-induced lesions in the PFC-HC

network

05/2017 **Belgian Society for Neuroscience** Ghent

Effect of MK801 on learning and memory

07/2016 **Federation of European Neurosciences** Copenhagen - Denmark

**Societies**Cognitive flexibility: Modulation of prefrontal-hippocampal network

### **Certificates and Courses**

03/2020	Introduction to SAS	FLAMES
01/2020	Python for Machine Learning	VSC - KU Leuven
01/2020	Python for Data Science	VSC - KU Leuven
01/2020	Scientific Python	VSC - KU Leuven

# **David Thonnard**

# Neuroscientist Data-analyst

Behavioural Testing

Morris Water Maze

▼ T-Maze

Rotarod

Open Field

Elevated Plus Maze

Touchscreen visual discrimination

Odor discrimination

Computer Skills

R

SAS

Python

SQL

Stata

SPSS

Matlab

✓ C

✓ LaTeX

A Driver's license: B (2004)

# Soft Skills



10/2019	Matlab programming introduction		VSC - KU Leuven
10/2019	Linux scripting		VSC - KU Leuven
12/2016	Non-parametric statistics	Leuven Statistics	s Research Centre
07/2014	FELASA C - Laboratory Animal Sciences	Biomedical Scie	ences - KU Leuven
03/2010	Vaccinations in the 21st century		Ghent University
02/2008	The tumor micro-environment: new insit therapeutic perspectives	ights and	Ghent University
03/2007	Viral infections during pregnancy and in Disease and bio-safety in the lab	n children.	Ghent University
2007	Kjeldahl method		Ghent University
2004	Business Management		OLVL Highschool

#### **Publications**

2021	Effects of orbitofrontal cortex and ventral hippocampus disconnec-
	tion on spatial reversal learning.
	Thonnard, D., Callaerts-Vegh, Z., D.'Hooge, R.
	Neuroscience Letters, 135711 <u>DOI</u>

2020 Comparison between touchscreen operant chambers and water maze to detect early prefrontal dysfunction in mice.

Van den Broeck, L., Hansquine, P., Sierksma, A., Thonnard, D., Vegh-

Callaerts, Z. & D'Hooge, R.

Genes, Brain and Behavior, e12695 DOI

2019 Differential effects of post-training scopolamine on spatial and

non-spatial learning tasks in mice

Thonnard, D., Callaerts-Vegh, Z., D.'Hooge, R. Brain Research Bulletin, 152, 52-62 <u>DOI</u>

2019 NMDA receptor dependence of reversal learning and the flexible

use of cognitively demanding search strategies in mice *Thonnard, D., Dreesen, E., Callaerts-Vegh, Z., D'Hooge, R.* 

Progress in Neuropsychopharmacology & Biological Psychiatry, 90,

235-244 DOI

2011 Oorzaken en gevolgen van een verhoogd glucose metabolisme bij

kanker

Thonnard, D., Vermeulen, S.

Tijdschrift van de Belgische Vereniging van Laboratorium Technolo-

gen, 38(1), 17-23 DOI

### **Extra-curricular Activities**

